Chase. Ride. Survive.
Twisters is a action, thriller film directed by Lee Isaac Chung.
As storm season intensifies, the paths of former storm chaser Kate Carter and reckless social-media
superstar Tyler Owens collide when terrifying phenomena never seen before are unleashed.
The pair and their competing teams find themselves squarely in the paths of multiple
storm systems converging over central Oklahoma in the fight of their lives.
Kate, played by Daisy Edgar-Jones.
Tyler, played by Glen Powell.
Javi, played by Anthony Ramos.
Boone, played by Brandon Perea.
Cathy, played by Maura Tierney.
Ben, played by Harry Hadden-Paton.
Twisters is a 2024 American disaster film serving as a
standalone sequel to Twister (1996).
The film was directed by Lee Isaac Chung from a screenplay by Mark L.
Smith, based on a story by Joseph Kosinski.
The ensemble cast includes Daisy Edgar-Jones, Glen Powell, Anthony
Ramos, Brandon Perea, Maura Tierney, and Sasha Lane.
It follows clashing groups of storm chasers who
investigate a tornado outbreak in Oklahoma.
Talks for a sequel to Twister began in 2020, with Kosinski pitching an idea to Universal Pictures and Helen Hunt,
who starred in the original, also expressing interest in a follow-up that was ultimately rejected.
Several directors were approached before Chung was hired in December 2022.
The cast joined in early-2023 and filming took place around Oklahoma that
summer, with a brief hiatus due to the SAG-AFTRA strike.
Twisters premiered at the Cineworld Leicester Square in London on July 8,
2024, and was released internationally by Warner Bros.
Pictures on July 10 and in the United States and
Canada by Universal Pictures on July 19.
It received generally positive reviews from critics
and grossed $372.3 million worldwide.
The film explores themes of dying and death, rodeo,
climate, twister, natural disaster.
The tone is intense and mind_bending.